1,500.
一千五
1,800.
一千八
I hear 1,800 from No.7.
七号先生出价一千八
1,800?
一千八百块
He can buy a small apartment with a little more money.
这再加点都可以买一套小公寓了
Yeah.
对啊
Whose son is this?
这是谁家的公子啊
He's careless about money.
花钱这么大手大脚的
Aren't his family afraid he'll dissipate their fortune?
这家里也不怕给败光了
1,800.
一千八
Is anyone bidding more than 1,800?
还有没有人
2,000.
两千
No.16 bid 2,000.
十六号先生出价两千
Is anyone bidding
还有没有哪位朋友
more than 2,000?
比出价两千更高的呢
2,000 going once.
两千块一次
2,000.
两千块
Going twice.
两次
Going thrice.
三次
Sold.
成交
- Good!
好 好 好
Congratulations to this gentleman for getting the jewelry.
恭喜这位先生获得珍宝
The bidding seems to be aggressive.
看这样子今天非常激烈啊
Yeah.
是啊
(Central China Antiques Charity Auction)
咱们这点 什么都不是啊
OK. Please.
好 有请
Please look here.
请看这边
- Here. Look here. - Look here.
来 看这里 看这里
Excuse me. Please look here.
您好 请看这里
Good.
不错
It suits you well.
很适合你
- Good!
好
- Congratulations!
恭喜恭喜啊 恭喜恭喜
Good.
好啊
Mrs. Qian. This way.
钱太太 这边
Those desserts are delicious.
那些小甜点可好吃了
Really? Let's go upstairs and have some.
是吗
Let's come here next time.
咱们一会在看看吧
Let's sit over there.
咱们去那边坐坐吧
You look beautiful today.
你今天可真美
But the gems are not fine enough.
只不过这宝石的成色不够好
I still think the south red agate fits you better.
我觉得还是那个南红玛瑙更衬你
It's a pity you don't like my agate.
可惜你不喜欢我送你的玛瑙
Which woman doesn't like nice jewelries?
哪个女人不喜欢漂亮的珠宝
What I mind is your motives for giving me gifts.
就要看他送礼物的动机了
Like just now,
好比刚才
what did you want me to say?
你让我说你什么好
What did I do?
我又做什么了
The necklace only costs several hundred yuan
一条几百块钱的项链
and you bid 2,000.
被你抬价到两千
Are you the decoy
你说你是不是拍卖公司
of the Auction House?
派来的托啊
If you hate Meng Xu'an,
你要是讨厌孟绪安
you should be grateful that I made him pay more.
就该谢我让他多掏了钱
If you like him,
你要是喜欢孟绪安
you should be more grateful
更应该谢我
that I tested him for you.
替你考验了他的心意
In short,
说来说去
you think I owe you a favor?
都是我欠你人情了
I like it when you owe me a favor.
我就是喜欢你欠着我人情
At least we have some bonds,
至少我们还能有些牵连
don't we?
不是吗
It was highly competitive just now.
刚才竞争太激烈了
Why aren't you with Miss Du?
你怎么没和杜小姐在一起啊
Let's come back later.
咱们一会儿再看看吧
She is expecting
她身子重
and in a bad mood.
心情不好
I don't want to annoy her.
我可不想招惹她
Expecting?
身子重
Do you mean...
你说她
It's not mine.
不是我的
What about you?
你呢
Meng Xu'an's junior?
孟绪安的师妹
Or what?
不然呢
Baoli thought I was bored all day long
宝丽见我整日无聊
and suggested bringing me to the auction.
说带我来拍卖会见见世面
Mr. Meng happened to be there.
恰好孟老板也在
He was willing to be my date.
乐意做我的男伴
Why should I say no?
我又何乐而不为啊
Meng Xu'an is really a gentleman.
这孟绪安还真是个绅士啊
Of all the social gatherings in Shanghai at the end of the year,
年末全上海有这么多社交会
why did he bring you to this auction?
偏偏带你来参加今天的拍卖会
What's special about this auction?
今天的拍卖会有什么特殊吗
By the way,
对了
what's going on with Fanglin?
芳林是怎么回事
Your family
你们家
don't want to
不会是想撮合
pair her off with that sickly man, do they?
她和那个病怏怏的男人在一起吧
It's just a perfunctory effort out of courtesy.
只是在场面上应付一下罢了
I hear Hashimoto Taichi
我可是听说那个桥本太一
has heart disease.
有心脏方面的疾病
Why doesn't he rest at home?
这样的人不在家里好好静养
Isn't he afraid of having any accidents
还出席什么拍卖会啊
at the auction?
也不怕出什么意外
A sick man also needs some time out of doors.
身子不好也该出来透透气吧
Besides,
再说了
it's just an auction.
不过是个拍卖会
What accidents can you expect?
能有什么意外
Meng Xu'an is quite charming.
孟绪安很有魅力
Is he the reason
你是因为他
why you've been turning me down?
所以才一直拒绝我吗
Why do you always bring him into this?
干吗总把他扯进来
Why do you always tangle with him?
那你为什么总和他牵扯不清
I have social activities, too.
我有我的社交
You interfere too much.
你干涉太多了
Besides, you're no better than me.
更何况你又好到哪去了
You have Du Lanxin
左边一个杜兰馨
and Hashimoto Shiori at the same time.
右边一个桥本诗织
Why don't you take care of the two women first
你先把这两个女人处理好
before you mind my business?
再来管我吧
My engagement to Du Lanxin
我和杜兰馨的婚约
will be broken off soon.
很快就会结束的
What about Hashimoto Shiori?
那桥本诗织呢
I won't get engaged to her.
我不会和桥本诗织订婚的
It's a dead end, Jiashang.
这是个死局 嘉上
Without Du Lanxin and Hashimoto Shiori,
没有杜兰馨 没有桥本诗织
there will be other women,
还会有别的女人
other rich families that want to connect with your family by marriage.
别的豪门
It's not the problem of women.
这不是女人的问题
The problem is
而是你的婚姻
you can't decide your own marriage.
你自己根本就不能做主
In this case,
这样的情况下
you still want me to promise you.
你还想让我给出你什么承诺
Don't you think it's selfish?
你不觉得你这样太自私了吗
Give me some more time.
你再给我一点时间
Six months.
半年
Would you wait for me for another six months?
你等我半年好不好
Six months later,
如果半年之后
if I'm still so disappointing,
我还是这么没有出息
you can marry Meng Xu'an.
你大可嫁给孟绪安
Why would I marry him?
我干嘛非要嫁给他啊
Besides,
而且
I can't wait for six months.
我等不了你半年
Let's get this straight.
我们把话说明白
How much time will you give me
你肯给我多少时间
so that I can fight for us?
为我们两个争取
Tonight.
今晚
Just tonight.
就今晚
What did you say?
你说什么
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗
I'm serious.
我是认真的
Right now.
就是现在
Will you go with me?
你肯跟我走吗
Where are we going?
去哪里
We can go anywhere.
随便去哪儿都行
Let's get two train tickets
买一张火车票
and leave here.
我们离开这儿
Leave your family and my family.
离开你家我家
Let's leave Shanghai.
我们离开上海
Are you testing me
你这是在考验我吗
or is it a hypothesis?
还是说这是个假设
Jiashang,
嘉上
you're not the same with them.
你跟他们不同的
You have ideals and ambition.
你是有理想有抱负的
You want a different life
你想过不同的人生
and you have the qualifications and abilities to pursue it.
而且你有条件和能力去追求
God has been good to you.
上天已经很眷顾你了
You shouldn't give up.
你就更不能放弃
Jiashang.
嘉上
Let's go. Leave here.
我们走吧 离开这儿
Say yes. Just say it.
说好 快说呀
Sorry, Shizhen.
对不起 世真
I'm the eldest son of my family.
我是家中的长子
Though I don't want to take over the family business,
就算我不想继承家业
I can't walk away like this.
我也不能这样任性地一走了之
Admit it or not,
不管你是不是承认
the Rong family is a giant ship that is destined to sink.
容家注定是一艘要沉没的船
Your father is doomed to failure.
你爹他多行不义必自毙
If you stay with him,
你跟着他这样下去
you'll be drawn into trouble step by step.
只会被他一步步拖进泥潭里
I know.
我知道
Who wouldn't want to
谁又不想自由自在
do whatever he likes freely?
做自己喜欢做的事情呢
But there are
但是容家
innocent members in my family.
还有其他无辜的家人们
I must protect them.
那我就必须保护他们
I have to take the responsibility,
肩负起这份责任
even if the giant ship
即使这艘大船
is destined to sink.
终将会驶向沉没
What about us?
那我们怎么办
You asked me to wait for you.
你让我等你
Do you want me to rescue you
难道是等这艘船沉没了以后
after the ship sinks?
让我来搭救你吗
Or do you think in six months,
还是你认为半年以后
your family will collapse?
容家就会倒台
Don't you yearn for the blue sky and white clouds?
你不是向往蓝天白云吗
You should fly
那你就应该驾驶着飞机
to the blue sky
在蓝天之上
and pursue whatever you want to.
追逐任何你想追逐的东西
I hate your father.
我痛恨厌恶你的父亲
But I really hope...
但是我真的希望
I really hope one day,
我真的希望有一天
I don't have to hate you.
我不要再厌恶你
Shizhen,
世真
what happened
发生什么事了
that makes you want to run away with me?
你竟然会和我说要私奔
You're always rational and restrained.
你一向是最理智克制的
It was a spur of the moment.
是我一时冲动
Just think of me as drunk.
你就当我喝醉了
No.
不
What else do you want?
你还想怎么样
Do you want me to say I'm so crazy about you
难道是我爱你爱得太疯狂了
that I can't wait for you to deal with your family mess
等不及你处理你们家那摊子烂事
to run away with you?
只想和你私奔吗
Shizhen.
世真
Jiashang.
嘉上
Leave with me tonight.
今晚跟我走
I'll do anything.
我就都听你的
I remember it.
我记着了
I remember everything you said today.
你今天说的话
The day will come when I leave with you.
会有让你兑现的那一天
The invitation is available
今晚说的话
just for tonight.
过期不候
Shizhen.
世真
I know what you feel now.
我知道你的心意了
I'm very touched.
我很感动
But there are things I have to do.
但是有些事情我不得不去做
Maybe in your opinion,
或许在你看来
I should give up my family
我可以放弃家族
for my future.
只要前途
But in my view,
但是在我看来
I want both.
我两样都要
I want to protect my family
我要保住家业
and fulfill my ambitions.
我也要实现理想
And you,
还有你
I want you, too.
我也要
He still doesn't
他还是不愿意
want to leave with you, does he?
跟你一起走啊
Did you
七爷
expect this?
早就料到了
Believe me.
相信我
It's his loss
他不肯走
that he doesn't leave with you.
那是他的损失
Not necessarily.
这倒未必呢
First,
一来
elopement never ends well.
私奔从来就没有什么好的结果
Second,
二来
though I don't know
虽然不知道容家
what plan do the Rong family have tonight,
今天晚上会有什么计划
but Rong Jiashang
但容嘉上这个人做事
is always careful.
一向是谨慎的
He may allow for unforeseen circumstances.
也许给自己留有余地也未可知
But you seem to
倒是七爷
have a well-thought-out plan
好似胸有成竹
and want me to see a big play.
想让我看什么大戏
I dare not say
是不是大戏
there will be a big play.
我暂且不敢说
You know me.
我这个人你知道的
I don't guarantee anything.
不喜欢把话说得太满
But women
不过你们女人
are all the same.
都是一样的
You would be crazy about love.
会因为爱情冲昏头脑
I knew a woman
我曾经亲眼见过一个女人
who once smiled like she smelt flowers in the air.
笑起来好像空气中带着花香一样
But in the end,
但是最后呢
she was devastated by love.
被爱情摧残得人不像人鬼不像鬼
In your words,
好像在七爷的口中
love always seems to be a dreadful monster.
爱情从来就是洪水猛兽
Have you never seen true happy love?
你就真的没有见过美好的爱情吗
It would be better if it's really
如果真的是洪水猛兽的话
a dreadful monster.
倒还好了
Everyone would avoid it, then.
人人可以避而远之
However,
但是
what is love really like?
爱情像什么
It's like opium.
它就像大烟一样
Smoking it once,
只要抽上一口
and you'll feel carefree and joyous
就让你心旷神怡
like treading on air.
飘飘欲仙
But as soon as it's cut off,
但一旦断了
you'll be miserable like hell.
会让你痛苦得生不如死
Such being the case,
与其如此
people shouldn't smoke it in the first place.
当初就不应该抽第一口
What should they do?
那可怎么办
They couldn't stop themselves
如果真的喜欢上一个人
from falling in love.
是由不得自己做主的
Those who can't curb their impulses
控制不住自己悸动的人
are usually weak.
往往都是弱者
But what should they do
可如果已经上瘾了
if they're already addicted to it?
该怎么办呢
Mrs. Rong, you're really lucky.
容太太真是有福气呀
You have a handsome and talented son
生的容少爷又帅气又有才
- as well as a beautiful daughter. - Have some water.
还生了一个漂亮的女儿
OK, thanks.
谢谢
Thanks.
哪里哪里
We're flattered.
过奖了
My big brother seems to like Fanglin very much.
看来大哥很喜欢芳林呢
Taichi doesn't look well.
我看太一脸色不大好
Does he need to go home and have a rest?
要不要先回家休息啊
Our children have a lot to talk about.
他们年轻人有很多话要说
Let's not
我们做长辈的
bother them.
不便干涉
Sure.
就是 就是
That's right.
说得是呢
Mrs. Rong, don't worry.
容太太放心
Taichi is in good health.
太一的身子没有问题的
Well, that's good.
那就好
Miss Rong,
容小姐
I'd like to have a drink.
我想喝杯酒
Would you drink with me?
能陪我取一杯吗
Sorry.
抱歉啊
It's embarrassing
第一次见面
for our first meeting.
就是这种尴尬的场合
It makes you uncomfortable.
让你不自在了
Are you unhappy because
是不是我的身体看起来很差
I look like in bad health?
让你不高兴了
No.
不是
Because my father pairs me off with you without asking my opinion.
是爹爹一声不吭就把我推向你
His intention is too obvious.
意图明显
That's what I hate.
我讨厌的是这个罢了
You seem to be an independent woman.
容小姐看起来是个很有主见的人
I don't think you would like an arranged marriage.
想来是不喜欢父母做的婚配的
Me too.
我也是
In Japan, there is a saying that
在我们日本啊有个说法叫
an instant, one second,
一瞬一秒
which means time is short.
形容时间短暂
Since we are both under pressure,
既然我们都是被形势所逼
we'd better get along as friends
不如以朋友的方式相处
and cherish the present.
珍惜现在的每一秒
How about that?
如何
Are you all right?
你没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
I'm used to it.
习惯了
It's my first time, too.
我也是第一次
Yeah.
对对对
Miss Feng.
冯小姐
I remember clearly.
我记得很清楚
Miss Xiao said she felt sick
肖小姐说她有些不舒服
and asked you to accompany her.
托我找您去陪陪她
What happened to her?
她怎么了
She seems to be drunk.
她好像喝多了 您快随我来吧
Let's go.
好
Please.
走
Mr. Meng.
七爷
How is Baoli?
宝丽怎么样了
Let her in.
让她进去吧
Miss Feng.
冯小姐
Hello, there.
你好啊
Meng Xu'an, open the door.
孟绪安 你把门开开
Keep Xiaojiu good company.
好好陪着小九吧
Have a guess when you get time.
有空的时候你猜一猜
Who will be the winner
今天晚上的赢家
of tonight?
到底会是谁
Meng Xu'an, what are you doing?
孟绪安你要干什么
Are you insane?
你疯了吗
Let me out.
放我出去
Let me...
放我
Xiaojiu,
九少
why did your big brother bring you here?
你大哥怎么把你带来了
He wants me to watch a play.
大哥带我来看戏的
Miss Feng, are you here to watch the play?
冯小姐也是来看戏的吗
Watch the play?
看戏
What does that mean?
什么意思啊
My brother said my daddy is down there.
大哥说 爹地就在这下面
Do you know who he is?
你知道哪个是吗
My brother will take me to see him later.
大哥待会儿要带我去见爹地
Do you think he will
你觉得我穿成这个样子
like my suit?
爹地会喜欢吗
How many people have your brother brought here to watch the play?
你大哥带了多少人来看戏
They all work for my brother.
这边都是我大哥的人
My brother said
大哥说
he would make Daddy acknowledge me.
一定会让爹地认我的
At that time,
到时候
he'll put that man...
他就会把那个人
He'll kill that man.
杀了那个人
Kill who?
杀了谁
Your daddy?
杀了你爹地
How could he kill my daddy?
怎么会杀了我爹地呢
He'll kill the man who took my birthright.
肯定杀了那个占我名分的人
Took your birthright?
占你名分
Who was it?
谁占你名分
Daddy's eldest son, of course.
当然是我爹地的大儿子了
My brother said,
大哥说
Daddy owes me and Mommy.
爹地欠我们母子的
He owes me all the property
容家所有的财产
of the Rong family.
都应该是我的
He also said,
大哥还说
Daddy misses me and Mommy very much.
爹地一直很牵挂我们母子
He'll be happy
所以爹地见到我
to see me.
一定会很开心的
Meng Xu'an doesn't care about the Gold Kylin at all.
孟绪安根本就不在乎什么金麒麟
He doesn't care
也不在乎
if Rong Dingkun apologizes to him.
容定坤会不会向他低头道歉
He wants Rong Jiashang's life,
他要的是
then present Rong Dingkun with a crippled and crazy son.
然后再给一个残病疯癫的儿子
He wants him to know
让他知道
what a terrible sin
他十六年前
he had committed 16 years ago.
到底造下了多沉重的罪孽
Crazy!
疯了
Meng Xu'an has gone crazy.
孟绪安他彻底疯了
He has no principles.
毫无原则
He won't hesitate to kill someone innocent.
不惜下手杀掉无辜的人
But what had
可是容嘉上
Rong Jiashang done wrong about it?
他在这件事里有什么错
Your brother left you here.
你大哥把你丢在这儿
What if you get sick?
如果你犯病了怎么办
The bodyguard has the pills.
保镖有药啊
And I'll behave,
而且
or Daddy may not acknowledge me.
要不然爹地不认我怎么办啊
But your brother just locked the door.
可是你大哥刚刚把门反锁了
How do you get the pills?
你怎么出去拿药
I have another key.
我还有一把钥匙
Where is it?
钥匙在哪儿
Miss Feng,
冯小姐
have a guess.
你猜猜看啊
Rest assured. I've notified the bank.
放心 我已经通知银行了
Great.
痛快
Do give us a chance to bid.
兄弟们得给一次出手机会
No problem.
没问题
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们
(Central China Antique Charity Auction) The next item up for bid
接下来即将要拍卖的
is the most closely watched
是本场拍卖会中
and the most expensive treasure
最受瞩目
in the auction,
也是最昂贵的珍宝
Gold Kylin.
金麒麟
I guess it may cost thousands of silver dollars.
我估计得几千大洋拿不下
Let's wait and see.
来 我们一起看看
It looks nice.
品相不错啊
Let me see.
我看看
This is the first time I see it.
我也是第一次看见
Mr. Hashimoto.
桥本社长
Did you donate it anonymously?
这个金麒麟是你匿名捐赠的
No.
不是
Are there two gold kylins?
难道有两个金麒麟
Are you all right?
你没事吧
Don't you feel well?
你不舒服吗
I didn't hear of it.
没听说呀
I've been looking for the Gold Kylin for years.
我找了这金麒麟这么多年
I didn't hear it was a pair.
没听说它是一对啊
They shouldn't be a pair.
应该不是一对的
Take a closer look at the Gold Kylin.
你们仔细看那个金麒麟
It looks exactly the same
它跟桥本家
with the one the Hashimotos have.
那个金麒麟的姿态一模一样
It faces to the right.
头是冲着右边的
If they're a pair,
如果是一对的话
it should face to the left.
头应该冲着左边
- Not possible.
不可能
If it's authentic,
如果这只是真的
the one the Hashimotos own...
那桥本家
Thanks.
谢谢
You didn't take a close look.
也没近看
You can't be sure.
做不得准的
Jiashang.
嘉上啊
Make sure you win it.
一会儿你把它拍下来
It can't fall into other hands.
这个东西不能落到别人手里
- Jiashang. - Yes.
你听到了吗
- Let me see. - Did you hear it?
我看看
Impossible, absolutely impossible.
不可能 不可能 绝对不可能
Uncle, don't worry.
世伯请放心
If your Gold Kylin
如果您的那个金麒麟
is in your house safe and sound,
还在家里好好放着
this one must be fake.
那么这个应该就是仿造品
Since I put an advertisement in the papers,
自我登报以来
I've seen many fakes.
也见过不少仿品
Father.
父亲
Taiji.
太二
Take your men home quickly.
赶紧带几个人回家看看
Check if the Gold Kylin is still there.
金麒麟还在不在 快
Yes, Father.
是 父亲
Taichi.
大哥
- Taichi!
大哥 太一
- Taichi, are you all right?
大哥 你没事吧 大哥
- Taichi. - What's going on?
太一
- Taichi, how do you feel? - Taichi.
大哥 你怎么样了
- Taichi, are you all right? - Don't worry.
大哥你没事吧
Does he have the pills?
药 药有没有带
- Take it easy. - Don't worry.
太太放心
He has the pills.
哥哥的药带了
Taichi, take the pills.
大哥 吃药
Taichi, take it easy.
太一 别慌啊
You'll feel better soon. Relax.
吃完药就好了 缓缓气
Take it easy.
别着急
Tell me.
告诉我
Tell me where the key is.
告诉我钥匙到底在哪儿
Where is the key?
钥匙在哪儿
I can't tell you.
我不能告诉你
My brother asked me not to tell you.
大哥让我不要告诉你
Your brother asked you
你大哥说了
to give me the key.
把钥匙给我
Look at me.
看着我
Do you know who I am?
你还记得我是谁吗
Who are you?
你是谁啊
You're Miss Feng.
你是冯小姐啊
I can't give it to you.
我可不能给你
(Central China Antique Charity Auction) The bidding of the final treasure,
本场的压轴之宝
the Gold Kylin,
金麒麟
starts at 20,000.
起价两万
Honorable guests, please bid.
请诸位嘉宾出价
21,000.
两万一
Good.
好
22,000.
两万二
Is anyone bidding more?
还有没有更高的价
22,000 from No.26.
二十六号出价两万二
60,000.
六万
- Good. - 60,000 already?
好 七号先生出价六万
Is anyone bidding more than 60,000?
还有没有比六万更高的价呢
It has multiplied.
涨了好几倍呀
70,000.
七万
- 70,000.
七万块 七万
I shouldn't have given birth to you.
我当初就不应该把你生下来
No, no, no!
不对
You're a monster.
你就是个怪物
I told you I don't like carnations!
我说过我不喜欢康乃馨
Why must you paint them?
你为什么还要画
You're the reason
都是因为你
why I become like this.
我才变成现在这个样子
You ruined me!
都是你毁了我
Tell me, why?
你说 为什么
Do you know you're wrong?
知道错了吗
Then tell me,
我 我不敢了
where is the key?
钥匙到底藏在哪儿
Tell me!
说
No, I can't tell you.
不 我不能告诉你
Don't you miss your daddy?
你不是想你爹地吗
Tell Mommy where the key is.
告诉妈咪钥匙在哪儿
Mommy will take you to Daddy.
妈咪带你一起去找好不好
Why can't you paint it well?
你为什么画不好
Really?
真的吗
Yes.
对
Really. Tell me
是真的 你跟我讲
where the key is.
钥匙在哪儿
Tell me
你告诉我
It's... it's under the floor.
在 在那个地板下面
Floor.
地板
Be good.
你听话
Do as Mommy told you.
听妈咪话
120,000.
十二万
Going once.
一次
Going twice.
两次
We don't have so much money.
我们哪有这么多钱
150,000.
十五万
Forget it.
算了算了
It's in increments of 30,000.
三万三万的加呀
Any more bidding?
有没有更高的价格
What's wrong with your son?
你儿子怎么回事啊
150,000.
十五万
- What do you women know? - 150,000 going once.
你们女人懂什么
- He doesn't own all your money. - 150,000 going twice.
家里的钱又不是他一个人的
You have other children.
你还有其他孩子呢
Aren't they your own children?
不是你亲生的
- Shut up. - Is there anyone who bids more?
闭嘴
Anyone who bids more?
有没有更高的价格
150,000.
十五万
170,000.
十七万
A high price of 170,000 from No.16.
十六号金主出了十七万的天价
(Central China Antique Charity Auction) Do I hear more bidding?
还有没有比十七万更高的价
Do I?
有没有
180,000.
十八万
What a lucky number!
多么吉利的数字
180,000 from No.7.
七号先生出价十八万
180,000.
十八万
Anyone who bids more at the back?
后面的老板有没有更高的价格
Anyone who bids more than 180,000?
哪位老板出价比十八万更高呢
180,000.
十八万
Going once.
一次
180,000 going twice.
十八万 两次
180,000.
十八万
Going thrice.
三次
Sold.
成交
- Good.
好
Congratulations to Mr. Rong
恭喜七号容先生
for getting the treasure.
获得至宝
We have troubles.
出事了
Send for a doctor.
快请医生
Xiaojiu passed out.
九少晕倒了
He almost has no pulse.
脉搏都快没了
- Yeah. - Yes.
好 是
Thanks for modestly declining it.
多谢孟老板谦让
You're welcome.
不用客气了
The Gold Kylin
这个金麒麟
must return to its owner.
总是要物归原主的
Sure.
一定
This way, please.
这边请
(Central China Antique Charity Auction)
只是有收藏价值的
Let's hear it for Mr. Rong.
来 掌声恭喜一下
- Congratulations!
恭喜啊 恭喜啊
Good.
好
Why is someone shooting?
怎么开枪了
What's going on?
怎么回事啊
Leave!
快走
Be careful!
小心点啊
Stop.
别打了
Taichi.
太一 太一
- Son.
儿子 太一
Master.
老爷
Get out of here.
先出去
- No. Fanglin is still here. - Go.
不行
Get out of here.
走
Jiashang.
嘉上
I can't watch them kill innocent people.
我不能让他们滥杀无辜
You leave first.
你先走
Jiashang.
嘉上
Miss Feng.
冯小姐
Don't go, will you?
您别去了好吗
Is Mr. Meng insane?
七爷这是疯了吗
Many innocent people died.
死了多少无辜的人
How could he wind this up?
接下来怎么收场
Miss Feng, I'm begging you.
冯小姐 算我求求你
Get out of here.
您还是快离开吧
You betrayed Mr. Meng.
您背叛了七爷
He is furious.
他现在非常生气
Could that be an excuse of killing people?
生气就可以随意杀人吗
He kills innocent people at will.
这样滥杀无辜的人
Are you still going to follow him?
你们还要追随吗
Leave her alone.
不用管她
I'm here.
在这儿呢
Catch Rong Jiashang.
追容家那小子
Go.
走
- Go!
追
- This way. - Hurry.
这边
- Boss. - Ah?
大哥
Where are your wife and children?
嫂子 孩子们呢
- Hurry. - I...
我
Go ahead. I'll save them.
你先走 我去救她们
Stop! Don't move!
站住 不许动 别乱跑
You, don't move!
你 别跑了
Stop, do you hear me?
站住 听见没有
- Stop!
站住 站住 不许动
Get out of my way!
滚开
Shujun, Shujun.
淑君
Are you all right?
怎么样 你没事吧
No, go to find Fanglin.
不行 快去找芳林
I can't live if something happens to her.
她出事了我怎么活呀
They're coming for your family.
是冲着容家来的
You're not safe staying here.
你留在这儿不安全
Find Fanglin. Go!
找芳林 快去
- Let me escort you out. - Find Fanglin.
我先送你出去
Hurry up.
快走
- Fanglin. - Go.
芳林
Go. Hurry up.
走 你们快走
- Stop! - Go away.
站住
Fanghua.
妹妹
Fanglin. You leave first.
姐 你快走
Go to ask Uncle Zhao to help us.
你快去找赵叔来救我们
No, you must leave with me.
不行 我得带你一起走
Yunchi.
云驰哥
Follow up.
快跟上
Guys, protect Boss.
弟兄们 保护七爷
- Be careful. - Go.
走
Are you all right, Fanglin?
你没事吧芳林
I'm fine.
我没事
Where is Fanghua?
芳桦呢
Go.
走
- Be careful. - They are coming.
小心啊
Be careful.
小心
What are you waiting for? Hurry!
想什么 快啊
What's wrong?
你怎么了
Where are you hurt?
伤到哪儿了
I'm bleeding.
流血了
- Taichi.
太一 大哥
Taichi. Taichi.
太一 太一
Taichi.
大哥 大哥 你没事吧 大哥
Taichi, don't die, Taichi.
大哥 你不能死啊 大哥
Rong Jiashang.
容嘉上
I'm impressed.
真是没想到啊
I really underestimated you.
我还真是小看你了
After killing half of my men,
干掉我一半手下
you still stand there unhurt.
还能好好地站在这儿
Tell me,
你说
if the headline on the front page of tomorrow's Shun Pao is
明日申报的头版头条是
"Mr. Rong Jiashang
容家大少爷容嘉上
Fell Off a Building
身中数枪
After Being Shot",
坠楼身亡
will it be dramatic?
效果会如何
Meng Xu'an, you're crazy.
孟绪安你疯了
I'm not crazy.
我没疯
I'm not the crazy one.
疯的人不是我
Xiaojiu,
小九
didn't you tell me
你不是一直跟我说
you wanted to see your own brother?
想见你亲大哥吗
He is your own brother.
这个人就是你亲大哥
Now you see him.
你见到了
Is he my brother?
就是他吗
Then, kill him quickly.
大哥那赶紧杀了他吧
Shoot him now.
你赶紧动手啊
Daddy will love me when he is dead.
你杀了他爹地就能喜欢我了
Do it now.
你赶紧动手吧
As blood brothers,
亲兄弟相见
don't you feel close to each other?
是不是分外亲切呀
Meng Jiu
孟九
is the only legacy
就是容定坤
Rong Dingkun left for the Meng family.
在孟家的沧海遗珠
I've been thinking.
我一直在想
I want the boy
想让这个孩子
to meet Rong Dingkun.
跟容定坤见上一面
Don't you think it's more fun
你说在他们俩见面的时候
if I present him with your dead body
再附上你的尸体
when they meet?
会不会更有意思啊
You want to kill me
你想杀了我
and make the lunatic the heir to the Rong family?
让这个疯子当容家的继承人
Meng Xu'an,
孟绪安
it turns out the whole thing about the Gold Kylin
原来金麒麟的事情
was a trap laid by you.
都是你的圈套
You set up the auction, too.
整个拍卖会都是你设计好的
You are not bad yourself.
你也不差啊
You made a fake Gold Kylin for the auction.
伪造了一个假的金麒麟来拍卖
You and your father
你们父子二人
went through a lot of trouble to find the treasure
为了把孟家的东西寻回来
of the Meng family.
真是煞费苦心
I am
孟某
very grateful.
十分感激
It's impolite not to reciprocate.
来而不往非礼也
Tell me,
你说
if I send such a big son
如果我把这么大一个儿子
to Rong Dingkun,
送到容定坤面前
will he shed tears
他会不会感激涕零
of gratitude?
泪流满面呢
An illegitimate son won't be acknowledged by the Rong family.
外面的野种是进不了容家大门的
Mr. Meng,
孟老板
your efforts are in vain.
你白费力气了
Miss Feng.
冯小姐
Let them drop the guns.
让他们把枪放下
I repeat,
我再说一遍
I've been thinking
我一直在盘算
when you will show up.
你会什么时候出现
I'm disappointed in you.
你真让我失望
Killing innocent people for revenge,
为了报仇不惜滥杀无辜
you're the one who is disappointing.
让人失望的人是你
Jiashang, leave.
嘉上
Come here.
你过来
Does Rong Jiashang know your secret?
容嘉上他知道你的秘密吗
Shut up.
你闭嘴
Shizhen.
世真
Come here.
你过来
Leave with me.
我带你一起走
Rong Dingkun tried every means
容定坤想尽一切办法
to help me find the Gold Kylin.
帮我找回金麒麟
Aren't you curious
你就不好奇
what I threatened him with?
我是用什么把柄来威胁他的吗
I don't care what you've got on him.
我不管你用了什么把柄
My father did a lot of evil things.
我爹做过的事情多了去了
It has something to do
这件事
with an elder brother and an elder sister of yours.
跟你的一对亲兄姐有关
I'm the eldest son of the Rong family.
我是容家唯一的长子
I don't have any elder brothers or sisters.
我没有什么兄姐
That's what he told you?
他是这么跟你说的
Shut up.
闭嘴
Shizhen.
世真
Come here.
你过来
Let's leave.
我们一起走
Don't move.
别过来
Are you all right?
没事吧
I'm fine.
没事
Get them!
追
- Yes!
是 是
Go.
走
This way, hurry!
这边 快点
Wait for me.
等等我
Be careful.
小心点啊
What are you doing?
干什么
- This is my car. - Take this.
这是我的车 这个给你
Here are the cars. Come on.
这
My car! My car!
我的车 我的车
Hop in. Go.
上车 追
Get them!
快点追
Hold on.
坐稳了
One, two.
一辆 两辆
There are two more cars.
又多了两辆车
Meng Xu'an is betting all on a single throw this time.
孟绪安这次真是下了血本
Let's see what he can do.
我倒要看他有多大能耐
Hold on.
坐稳
Boss.
七爷
Rong Jiashang
这个容嘉上
seems to be going around in circles.
好像带着我们在兜圈子
Will there be a trap?
会不会有诈
Catch up with them.
追上他们
Yes.
是
We're trapped.
我们被困住了